（特别放送）
（华盛顿州 西雅图）
（一年前）
圣诞快乐 爷爷
Merry Christmas, Grandpa.
你也圣诞快乐 史蒂文
Merry Christmas to you, Stevey.
你给我带礼物来了吗
Did you bring me any presents?
我为什么要带礼物来呢
Now, why would I wanna do that?
因为今天是圣诞节
Because it's Christmas.
圣诞节带礼物来的不是圣诞老人吗
I thought Santa Claus brought the presents at Christmas.
你今年是个乖孩子吧
You have been a good boy this year, haven't you?
我是 我发誓
I have, I swear.
那好啊 谁知道呢 或许他会来
Well, then. Who knows? Maybe he'll come.
圣诞老人
Santa.
驯鹿
Reindeer.
圣诞老人
Santa?
[邪恶力量 第3季第8集]
（密歇根州 伊普西兰蒂）
（现今）
我女儿和我当时在床上
My daughter and I were in our beds.
迈克在楼下装饰圣诞树
Mike was downstairs decorating the tree.
我听到屋顶传来一记重响
And I heard a thump on the roof.
然后我听到了迈克尖叫
and then I heard Mike scream…
现在 我在接受联调局的询问
and now I'm talking to the FBI.
你什么都没看到吗
You didn't see any of it?
没有 他…
No, he was…
他就不见了
He was just gone.
门锁着 也没有强行闯入的迹象
The doors were locked, there was no forced entry?
是的
That's right.
还有其他人有钥匙吗
Does anybody else have a key?
我父母
My parents.
他们住哪
Where do they live?
佛罗里达州
Florida.
多谢你让我到处看看 沃什太太
Thanks for letting me have a look, Mrs Walsh.
我想我们已得到了我们需要的一切
I think we got just about everything we need.
我们完事了
We're all set.
我们会再联系的
We'll be in touch.
探员们
Agents.
警方说我丈夫可能是被绑架了
The police said my husband might've been kidnapped.
有可能
Could be.
那绑匪怎么还不来电话
Then why haven't the kidnappers called?
或索要赎金
Or demanded a ransom?
还有三天就圣诞节了
It's three days until Christmas.
我要怎么跟我们女儿说
What am I supposed to tell our daughter?
我们很遗憾
We're very sorry.
有发现吗
Find anything?
长袜 槲寄生
Stockings, mistletoe,
还有这个
this.
一颗牙
A tooth?
- 对 - 在哪发现的
- Yeah. - Where was this?
烟囱里
In the chimney.
烟囱 一个男人不可能钻进烟囱里
Chimney? No way a man fits up a chimney,
太窄了
it's too narrow.
一个完整的人进不去
No way he fits up in one piece.
好吧 如果爸爸是顺烟囱上去了
All right. So if dad went up the chimney…
我们得找到把他拽上去的东西
We need to find out what dragged him up there.
我是对的吗
So was I right?
是连环杀人扫烟囱工吗
Is it the serial killing chimney sweep?
嗯 其实是迪克·范·戴克
Yup, it's actually Dick Van Dyke.
谁
Who?
- 玛丽·波平斯 - 那又是谁
- Mary Poppins… - Who's that?
拜托
Come on…
算了
Never mind.
原来 沃什是本月镇上第二个
Well, turns out, that Walsh is the second guy in twon.
被从家里抓走的人了
grabbed out of his house this month.
- 是吗 - 嗯
- Yeah? - Yeah.
另一个人也是被从烟囱拽上去的吗
Did the other guy get dragged up the chimney too?
不知道 目击者只说听到屋顶传来重响
Don't know. Witnesses said they heard a thump on the roof.
你觉得这是个什么东西
So what the hell you think we are dealing with?
其实 我有个想法
Actually, I have an idea.
是吗
Yeah?
听上去会很疯狂
It's gonna sound crazy.
你说什么会让我觉得疯狂
What could you possibly say that sounds crazy to me?
邪恶圣诞老人
Evil Santa.
好吧 那是疯狂
Yeah, that's crazy.
嗯
Yeah.
我就是说
I mean, I'm just saying that.
每种文化里都有某种反圣诞老人
there's some version of the Anti-Claus in every culture.
贝尔斯尼克 克朗普斯 黑彼得
You got Belsnickel, Krampus, Black Peter.
不管你怎么称呼它 有各种相关传说
Whatever you wanna call it. There's all sorts of lore.
什么内容
Saying what?
就是想当年 圣诞老人的弟弟变坏了
Saying, back in the day, Santa's brother went rogue.
现在他会在圣诞节时出现
And now he shows up around Christmas time,
但他不带来礼物 而是惩罚坏人
but instead of bringing presents, he punishes the wicked.
把他们拽上烟囱吗
By hauling their ass up chimneys?
这是个开头吧
For starters, yeah.
这是你的理论吗
So this is your theory?
圣诞老人的坏弟弟
Santa's shady brother?
我…就是说 这是传说的内容
Well, I… Just saying, that's what the lore says.
圣诞老人没有弟弟 根本没有圣诞老人
Santa doesn't have a brother. There is no Santa.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
当初还是你告诉我的呢 记得吗
You're the one who told me that in the first place, remember?
知道吗 我可能错了
Yeah, you know what, I could be wrong, I…
肯定是错了
Gotta be wrong.
或许不是
Maybe, maybe not.
什么
What?
我去查了查
I did a little digging.
原来两名受害人被抓前
Turns out, both victims visited the same place,
都去过同一个地方
before they got snatched.
什么地方
Where?
（欢迎来到圣诞老人村）
快点
Hurry up.
快
Hurry.
这让理论有点可信度了 是吧
It does kind of lend credence to the theory, don't it?
嗯 但反圣诞老人
Yeah, but Anti-Claus?
不可能的
Couldn't be.
这是圣诞奇迹
It's a Christmas miracle.
说起来 我们今年该过一次
Speaking of, we should have one this year.
- 过一次什么 - 圣诞节
- Have one what? - A Christmas.
不了 谢谢
No, thanks.
不 我们弄棵树
No, we'll get a tree…
买点快餐回来 就像我们小时候那样
a little Boston Market, just like when we were little.
迪恩 小时候的记忆对我来说没那么温馨
Dean, those weren't exactly Hallmark memories for me, you know.
你说什么呢 我当年有些圣诞节很棒的
What you talking about? We had some great Christmases.
你说的是谁的童年啊
Who's childhood are you talking about?
拜托 萨姆
Come on, Sam.
不
No, just…
不要
No.
好吧 圣诞怪杰
All right, grinch.
（内布拉斯加州 布罗肯鲍）
（1991年平安夜）
那是什么
What is that?
给爸爸的礼物
Present for dad.
得了吧
Yeah, right.
你哪来的钱 偷的吗
Where did you get the money? Steal it?
不是
No.
是鲍比叔叔给我送他的
Uncle Bobby gave it to me to give to him.
说它很特别
Said it was real special.
是什么
What is it?
小马
A pony.
真逗
Very funny.
爸爸会回来吧
Dad's gonna be here, right?
他会回来的
He'll be here.
但这可是圣诞节
But it's Christmas.
他知道
He knows.
他会回来的 我保证
And he'll be here. Promise.
他去哪了
Where is he anyway?
办事去了
On business.
什么样的事
What kind of business?
你知道的
You know that.
他卖东西
He sells stuff.
什么东西
What kind of stuff?
就东西
Stuff.
谁都不肯告诉我事
Nobody ever tells me anything.
那就别问了
Then quit asking.
爸爸是间谍吗
Is dad a spy?
他是007
He's James Bond.
我们为什么老搬家
Why do we move around so much?
因为不管我们去哪 人们都会厌烦你
Because everywhere we go, they get sick of your face.
我够大了 迪恩 你可以告诉我实话
I'm old enough, Dean. You can tell me the truth.
你不想知道实情
You don't wanna know the truth.
相信我
Believe me.
所以我们才从不谈起妈妈吗
Is that why we never talk about mom?
闭嘴
Shut up!
你永远不许提起妈妈 永远不许
Don't you ever talk about mom, ever!
等等 你去哪
Wait, where are you going?
出去
Out.
花了10块才进来
You'd think for the 10 bucks it costs to get into this place,
圣诞老人也不弄点雪出来
Santa could scrounge up a little snow.
什么
What?
没事 我们要找什么来着
Nothing. What are we looking for again?
根据传说 反圣诞老人走路跛脚
Lore says that the Anti-Claus will walk with a limp…
还一身甜味儿
and smell like sweets.
好啊 我们要找个皮条客圣诞老人
Great, so we're looking for a pimp Santa.
为什么有甜味儿
Why the sweets?
想想看 迪恩 如果你一身糖味儿
Think about it, Dean. If you smell like candy,
孩子会乐意靠近你
the kids will come closer, you know?
真瘆人
That's creepy.
这玩意怎么知道谁乖谁不乖
How does this thing know who's been naughty and who's been nice?
我不知道
I don't know.
罗尼 来坐在圣诞老人膝盖上
So, Ronny, come sit on Santa's knee.
好了
There you go.
- 你今年乖不乖 - 乖
- You've been a good boy this year? - Yeah.
很好
Good.
圣诞老人有特别礼物给你
Santa's got a special gift for you.
或许我们知道了
Maybe we do.
来吧 亲爱的
Come on, honey.
- 好 - 走吧
- All right. - Let's go.
欢迎来到圣诞老人之家
Welcome to Santa's Court.
要我带你们的孩子去见圣诞老人吗
Can I escort your child to Santa?
不了
No, no.
但其实 我弟弟这辈子一直想见圣诞老人
But actually, my brother here, it's been a lifelong dream of his.
抱歉
Sorry.
- 仅限12岁以下儿童 - 不
- No kids over 12. - No,
他开玩笑的
he's just kidding.
我们只是来看的
We only came here to watch.
我不是说我们…
I didn't mean that we came here to…
多谢了 迪恩 多谢你了
Thanks a lot, Dean. Thanks for that.
看啊
Check it out.
没事
It's all right.
你看到了没有
Are you seeing this?
很多人走路跛脚
A lot of people walk with limps, right?
你难道没闻到吗 那是糖果味儿
Tell me you didn't smell that? That was candy, man.
那是果酒
That was ripple.
好像是吧 肯定是
I think. Had to be.
可能吧 我们要冒险吗
Maybe. We're willing to take that chance?
几点了
What time is it?
跟你上次问时没变化
Same as the last time you asked.
给
Here.
咖啡因
Caffeinate.
太好了
Wonderful.
萨姆
Sam.
嗯
Yeah?
你为什么成了个讨厌圣诞节的男孩
Why are you the boy that hates Christmas?
迪恩
Dean.
我承认
I mean, I admit it.
我们小时候有些节日不怎么平顺
You know, we had a few bumpy holidays when we were kids.
- 不平顺 - 但那是那时了
- Bumpy? - But that was then.
我们今年好好过
We'll do it right this year.
迪恩 如果你想过圣诞节 请便吧
Look, Dean, if you wanna have Christmas, knock yourself out.
别扯上我
Just don't involve me.
好啊 那肯定好
Yeah. That would be great.
我自己做酸梅糕
Me and myself making cranberry molds.
圣诞老人干什么呢
What's up with Saint Nicotine?
天啊
My God!
- 怎么了 - 没事
- What? - Nothing.
就是…
It's just that…
一心要过圣诞节的男人
Well, you know, Mr. Gung-Ho Christmas.
可能要崩了圣诞老人了
might have to blow away a Santa.
你们来干什么
The hell you doing here?
我真的不感兴趣 好吗
I'm really not interested, okay?
揉我的脚趾
Mistle my toe.
摸我的胸
Roast my chestnut.
我…
I…
摇我的铃铛
Jingle my bell.
*平安夜*
*Silent night*
*圣善夜*
*Holy night*
*真宁静*
*All is calm*
*真光明*
*All is bright*
- *光明…* - *圣光…*
- *Bright…* - *Round…*
我们走吧
Let's go.
圣诞老人 你来早了
Santa, you're early.
你儿子是这样描述袭击的吗
So that's how your son described the attack?
圣诞老人把爸爸拽上了烟囱
Santa took daddy up the chimney?
他是这么说的
That's what he says, yes.
你当时在哪
And where were you?
我当时在睡觉
I was asleep.
突然间
And all of a sudden,
艾尔就尖叫着被从床上拽了下来
Al was being dragged out of bed, screaming.
你看到袭击者了吗
Did you see the attacker?
当时太黑
It was dark.
他打了我
and he hit me.
他打晕了我
He knocked me out.
很抱歉 我知道这很难
I'm sorry. I know this is hard.
嗯
Yeah.
考德威尔太太 壁炉上那个花环你哪买的
Mrs. Caldwell, where did you get that wreath above the fireplace?
什么
Excuse me?
就是想问问
Just curious, you know?
花环
Wreaths, huh?
你不问问她哪买的鞋吗
Sure you didn't wanna ask her about her shoes?
我还在门厅里看到了不错的手包
I saw some nice handbags in the foyer.
- 我们见过那个花环 迪恩 - 在哪
- We've seen that wreath before, Dean. - Where?
沃什家
The Walsh's.
就昨天
Yesterday.
我知道 我就试你呢
I know. I was just testing you.
嗯 好
Yeah. All right.
那麻烦你继续查吧
Well, keep looking, would you?
谢谢 鲍比
Thanks, Bobby.
好吧
Well,
我们要对付的不是反圣诞老人
we're not dealing with the Anti-Claus.
鲍比怎么说
What did Bobby say?
我们是白痴
That we're morons.
他还说 花环里的可能是绣线菊
He also said that it was probably meadowsweet in those wreaths.
真棒啊
Amazing.
绣线菊是什么
What the hell is meadowsweet?
很稀有
It's pretty rare.
而且可能是异教传说里最强大的植物了
and it's probably the most powerful plant in pagan lore.
异教传说
Pagan lore?
对
Yeah.
他们用绣线菊做人祭
See, they'd use meadowsweet for human sacrifices.
就像给他们神的诱饵
It was kind of like a chum for their gods.
神被它吸引 他们便会来做客
Gods were drawn to it, and they'd stop by and.
并吃掉最近的人类
snack on whatever was the nearest human.
为什么会有人用那个做圣诞节花环
Why would somebody be using that for Christmas wreaths?
并不像听上去那么离谱 迪恩
It's not as crazy as it sounds, Dean. I mean,
圣诞节传统基本上都是异教的
pretty much every Christmas tradition is pagan.
圣诞节是耶稣的生日
Christmas is Jesus' birthday.
不 耶稣的生日八成是在秋季
No, Jesus' birthday was probably in the fall.
其实是冬至节
It was actually the winter solstice festival,
被教会改成了圣诞节
that was co-opted by the Church and renamed Christmas.
但圣诞柴 圣诞树 甚至圣诞老人的红装
But I mean, the yule log, the tree, even Santa's red suit,
那都是异教崇拜遗留下来的
that's all remnants of pagan worship.
你怎么会知道这些
How do you know that?
你接下来还要说什么 复活节兔子是犹太教的吗
What will you tell me next? Easter bunny's Jewish?
你觉得这是个异教神吗
So you think we're dealing with a pagan god?
嗯 可能是霍根尼卡
Yeah, probably Holdenacar…
冬至之神
god of the winter solstice.
结果那些家装迷买了些高档花环回家
And all these Martha Stewart wannabes buying these fancy wreaths.
嗯 差不多就像在家门口
Yup, it's pretty much like putting a neon sign.
挂了块霓虹灯牌 写着「来杀我们」
on your front door saying: "Come kill us."
好啊
Great.
向霍根尼卡做人祭
When you sacrifice to Holdenacar,
猜猜你能得到什么
guess what he gives you in return?
希望是大腿舞
Lap dances, hopefully.
温和天气
Mild weather.
就像密歇根州中部大12月的
Kinda like no snow in the middle of December.
却不下雪
in the middle of Michigan.
对
For instance.
我们知道怎么杀它吗
Do we know how to kill it, yet?
不知道 鲍比在查呢
No, Bobby's working on that right now.
我们得查到花环是哪卖的
We gotta figure out where they're selling those wreaths.
你觉得是有人故意在卖吗
Think they're selling them on purpose?
给这玩意投食
Feeding the victims to this thing?
我们查查看吧
Let's find out.
- 有什么我能帮你们的吗 - 希望有
- Can I help you, boys? - I hope so.
我们那天晚上去沃什家玩层层叠
We were playing Jenga over at the Walsh's the other night and…
他此后便一直张口闭口都是那个圣诞花环
Well, he hasn't shut up since about this Christmas wreath.
我说不清楚 你说吧
I don't know. You tell him.
好啊
Sure.
太香了
It was yummy.
我卖过很多花环
I sell a lot of wreaths, guys.
嗯 但是
Right, right, but you see,
这个很特别
this one would have been really special.
上面有绿叶 白芽
It had… It had green leaves, white buds on it.
可能是用绣线菊做的
Might have been made of meadowsweet?
你还真挑剔呢
Well, aren't you a fussy one?
是啊
He is.
反正 我知道你指的是哪个 我卖光了
Anyway, I know the one you're talking about. I'm all out.
看来这绣线菊什么的
Well, seems like this meadowsweet stuff's.
很稀有又昂贵
pretty rare and expensive.
怎么会用它来做花环
Why make wreaths out of it?
不知道 不是我做的
Beats me. I didn't make them.
谁做的
Who did?
一位本地女士 玛姬·卡里根
Madge Carrigan, a local lady.
她说这花环很特别 免费送给了我
Said the wreaths were so special, she gave them to me for free.
- 她没收你钱吗 - 没
- She didn't charge you. - Nope.
你也免费送了吗
Did you sell them for free?
当然没 现在是圣诞节
Hell, no. It's Christmas…
人们愿为这破玩意付大钱呢
people pay a butt-load for this crap.
这才是圣诞精神啊
That's the spirit.
你觉得绣线菊花环得要多少钱
How much do you think a meadowsweet wreath would cost?
至少几百
Couple hundred dollars, at least.
这女人免费送出去
This lady's giving them away for free?
你怎么看
What do you think about that?
我觉得很可疑
Well, I'd say it's pretty suspicious.
记得爸爸有一年拿回家来的那个花环吗
Remember that wreath Dad brought home that one year?
他从一家酒水店偷回来的那个吗
You mean, the one he stole from, like, a liquor store?
嗯 一堆空啤酒罐做的
Yeah, it was a bunch of empty beer cans.
那玩意真棒
That thing was great.
嗯 我敢说如果我好好找
Yeah. I bet if I looked around hard enough,
能找到个一样的
I could probably find one just like it.
好吧
All right.
哥们
Dude,
你是怎么了
what's going on with you?
什么怎么了
What?
你怎么化身唱《白色圣诞节》的平·克劳斯贝了
I mean, since when are you Bing Crosby all of a sudden?
你为什么那么想过圣诞节
Why do you wanna do Christmas so bad?
你为什么那么反对
Why are you so against it?
你的童年记忆就那么惨烈吗
I mean, were your childhood memories that traumatic?
不是 跟那无关
No. That has nothing to do with it.
那是怎么了
Then what?
我…
I mean, I just…
我不懂
I don't get it.
你好几年都没提过圣诞节了
You haven't talked about Christmas in years.
是啊
Well, yeah.
这是我最后一年了
This is my last year.
我知道
I know.
所以我才做不到
That's why I can't.
什么意思
What do you mean?
我无法这么坐着
I mean, I can't just sit around.
喝蛋酒 假装一切都好
drinking eggnog, pretending everything's okay…
与此同时心知 明年圣诞节你就不在了
when I know next Christmas you'll be dead.
我就是做不到
I just can't.
还以为你出去了
Thought you went out?
嗯 去给你买晚餐
Yeah, I had to got you dinner.
别忘记吃蔬菜
Don't forget your vegetables.
我知道你为什么在枕头下藏枪
I know why you keep a gun under your pillow.
不 你不知道
No, you don't.
别乱翻我的东西
Stay out of my stuff.
我也知道为什么我们不论去哪都撒盐圈
And I know why we lay salt down everywhere we go.
你不知道 闭嘴吧
No, you don't. Shut up.
你哪拿来的 那是爸爸的
Where did you get that? That's dad's.
他知道你看了会扁你的
He's gonna kick your ass for reading that.
- 怪物是真的吗 - 什么
- Are monsters real? - What?
- 你疯了 - 告诉我
- You're crazy. - Tell me.
我发誓 如果你敢告诉爸爸
I swear, if you ever tell dad.
我跟你说了这些 我就灭了你
I told you any of this, I will end you.
保证不说
Promise.
首先你要知道
First thing you have to know is.
我们有世上最酷的爸爸
we have the coolest dad in the world.
他是个超级英雄
He's a superhero.
是吗
He is?
嗯
Yeah.
怪物是真的
Monsters are real.
爸爸对抗它们
Dad fights them.
他现在就在打怪物
He's fighting them right now.
但爸爸说我床下的怪物不是真的
But dad said the monsters under my bed weren't real.
因为他已经检查过那里了
That's because he'd already checked under there.
但是 它们是真的
But, yeah, they're real.
几乎所有怪物都是真的
Almost everything's real.
圣诞老人是真的吗
Is Santa real?
不是
No.
如果怪物是真的
If monsters are real,
它们就能抓到我们 能抓到我
then they could get us. They could get me.
爸爸不会允许它们抓到你的
Dad's not gonna let them get you.
但如果它们抓到他呢
But what if they get him?
它们抓不到他的
They aren't gonna get dad.
爸爸是最厉害的了
Dad's, like, the best.
我在爸爸的日记里读到 它们杀了妈妈
I read in dad's book that they got mom.
那说来话长 萨姆
It's complicated, Sam.
如果它们能杀妈妈 就能杀爸爸
If they got mom, they can get dad.
如果它们能杀爸爸 就能杀我们
And if they get dad, they can get us.
不会那样的
It's not like that.
爸爸没事
Okay, dad's fine.
我们没事
We're fine.
相信我
Trust me.
你没事吧
You okay?
嗯
Yeah.
爸爸圣诞节会回来的
You know, dad's gonna be here for Christmas.
他总会回来
Just like he always is.
我只想睡觉 好吗
I just wanna go to sleep, okay?
嗯 好
Yeah, okay.
等你醒来一切都会好的
It'll all be better when you wake up.
等着瞧吧
You'll see.
我保证
Promise.
花环太太就住这里吗
So this is where Mrs. Wreath lives?
天啊 感觉到那股邪恶的异教气息了吧
Boy, can't you just feel the evil, pagan vibe?
你们好
Yes?
请告诉我你是玛姬·卡里根
Please, tell me you're the Madge Carrigan.
绣线菊花环的制作者
who makes the meadowsweet wreaths.
我是
Why, yes I am.
- 找到了 - 嗯
- Bingo. - Yeah.
我们那天在塞勒先生家
Well, we were just admiring your wreaths.
看到了你的花环 很喜欢
at Mr. Silar's place the other day.
是吗
You were?
那绣线菊
Isn't that meadowsweet.
是不是你闻过的最香的东西
just the finest smelling thing you ever smelled?
是的 真是的
It is. It sure is.
但问题是 你的花环都卖光了
But see the problem is that all your wreaths had sold out,
- 我们还没来得及买到一个 - 倒霉
- before we got the chance to buy one. - Fudge.
你不会还有一个
You wouldn't happen to have another one,
我们可以买走吧
that we can buy from, would you?
恐怕没有了
No. I'm afraid.
本季我只做了那么多
those were the only ones I had for this season.
告诉我
Tell me something.
你怎么会决定用绣线菊做花环
Why'd you decide to make them out of meadowsweet?
当然是因为气味
Why, the smell, of course.
我觉得我就没闻过那么香的东西
I don't think I've smelled anything finer.
嗯
Yeah.
你提过了
You mentioned that.
怎么回事 亲爱的
What's going on, honey?
就是俩好小伙儿来打听我的花环 亲爱的
Well, just some nice boys, asking about my wreaths, dear.
那花环真棒 好花环
The wreaths are fine. Fine wreaths.
来点花生糖吗
Care for some peanut brittle?
不用了
We're okay.
我就知道
I knew it.
那俩人非常不对劲
Something was off with those two.
你有什么发现
What did you find?
卡里根夫妇去年住在西雅图
The Carrigans lived in Seattle last year…
圣诞节期间 发生了两起绑架案
where two abductions took place, right around Christmas.
他们1月搬来了这里
They moved here in January.
他们家的圣诞节装饰可不是冬青树枝
All that Christmas crap in their house wasn't boughs of holly,
而是马鞭草和薄荷
it was vervain and mint.
异教的东西吗
Pagan stuff?
很厉害的异教东西
Serious pagan stuff.
怎么 那对看似普通的夫妻把一个异教神
So what? Ozzie and Harriett are keeping a pagan god.
藏在了他们裹着塑料膜的沙发下吗
hidden underneath their plastic covered couch?
我不知道
I don't know.
我只知道我们该去看看他们
All I know is we gotta check them out.
那鲍比呢
So what about Bobby?
他确定常青木桩能杀了他们 是吧
He's sure evergreen stakes will kill this thing, right?
是 他确定
Yeah, he's sure.
看 塑料膜
See, plastic.
迪恩
Dean.
萨姆
Sam!
天啊 我真希望你们没到下面来
Gosh, I wish you boys hadn't come down here.
迪恩
Dean?
你没事吧
Are you okay?
好像没事
Yeah, I think so.
看来他们是神夫妻
So I guess we're dealing with Mr. And Mrs. God.
- 至少知道了 - 嗯
- Nice to know. - Yeah.
我们还以为你俩懒骨头
And here we thought you two lazybones.
要把有趣的部分睡过去呢
were gonna sleep straight through all the fun stuff.
错过这个吗
And miss all this?
不 我们喜欢派对
No, we're partiers.
他多逗啊 亲爱的
Isn't he a kick in the pants, honey?
你们是猎人
You're hunters, is what you are.
嗯 你们是异教神
Yeah, and you're pagan gods.
我们就算扯平了
So why don't we just call it even and.
各走各路吧
go our separate ways?
怎么 让你带更多猎人回来 杀了我们吗
What, so you can bring back more hunters and kill us?
别想了
I don't think so.
或许你吃人之前
Maybe you should have thought that.
该想到这点的
before you went snacking on humans then.
得了 别那么激动
Now, don't get all wet.
我们以前每年能吃上百个祭品呢
Why, we used to take over a hundred tributes a year.
那是真的
And that's a fact.
现在我们才吃几个 两三个吧
Now, what do we take, what, two, three?
加上这俩侦探小伙儿就五个了
Hardy Boys here make five.
这还不错嘛
Now, that's not so bad, is it?
你这么说的话 你们就是模范夫妻了
Well, you say it like that, I guess you guys are the Cunninghams.
你先生 最好对我们放尊重点
You mister, better show us a little respect.
否则呢
Or what?
- 你要吃了我们吗 - 还不急
- You'll eat us? - Not so fast.
还要先遵守一些仪式
There's rituals to be followed first.
我们非常看重仪式
We're just sticklers for ritual.
知道仪式从什么开始吗
And you know what kicks off the whole shebang?
我猜猜 绣线菊
Let me guess. Meadowsweet.
该死 你们没有花环了
Shucks, you're all out of wreaths.
那只能取消人祭了
I guess we'll just have to cancel the sacrifice.
别那么消极
Don't be such a gloomy Gus.
好了
There.
他们看上去多可爱
Don't they just look darling?
可以吃了
Good enough to eat.
好咯
Alrighty-roo,
第二步
step number two.
萨姆
Sammy.
- 不 - 萨姆
- No. - Sammy?
不 别
No, no, don't.
放开他 你个混蛋
Leave him alone, you son of a bitch!
听听他们怎么跟我们说话
You hear how they talk to us?
我们可是神
To gods?
听好 伙计 想当年
Listen, pal, back in the day,
有数百万人崇拜我们呢
we were worshipped by millions.
时过境迁了
Times have changed.
可不是呢
Tell me about it.
突然间
All of a sudden, this.
这个耶稣成了新红人
Jesus character's the hot, new thing in town.
突然间 我们的祭坛被烧
All of a sudden, our altars are being burned down.
我们像普通怪物一样被猎杀
and we're being hunted down like common monsters.
但我们说什么了吗
But did we say peep?
没有 我们没有
No, no, no, we did not.
两千年啊
Two millennium.
我们低调做人 我们找了工作 按揭买房
We kept a low profile, we got jobs, a mortgage.
那个词怎么说的来着 亲爱的
We… What was that word, dear?
我们被同化了
We assimilated.
对 我们被同化了
Yeah, we assimilated.
我们周二和周五还打桥牌呢
Why, we play bridge on Tuesdays and Fridays.
我们跟其他人一样
We're just like everybody else.
你们没有你想得融入得那么好 女士
You're not blending in as smooth as you think, lady.
这可能会有点刺痛 亲爱的
This might pinch a bit, dear.
你个贱人
You bitch!
天啊
My goodness, me.
某人该往脏话罐里投五分了
Somebody owes a nickel to the swear jar.
知道我想说脏话时会说什么吗
Do you know what I say when I feel like swearing?
倒霉
Fudge.
我会尽量记住的
I'll try and remember that.
你们不知道你们多么幸运
You boys have no idea how lucky you are.
曾经 孩子们会远道而来
There was a time when kids came from miles around,
只为坐在你们这位置上
just to be sitting where you are.
你想拿那玩意干什么
What do you think you're doing with those?
你倒霉催的敢再碰我 我宰了你
You fudging touch me again, I'll fudging kill you!
很好
Very good.
不不 别
No. No, don't.
拔到了
We've got a winner.
还有什么 亲爱的
What else, dear?
我看看
Well, let's see.
指甲 血
Fingernail, blood.
老天爷啊
Sweet Peter on a Popsicle stick.
我忘了牙
I forgot the tooth.
天啊
Dear.
圣诞快乐 萨姆
Merry Christmas, Sam.
张大嘴 说「啊」
Open wide and say: Aah.
谁要去开门吗
Somebody gonna get that?
你们该去开门
You should get that.
走吧
Come on.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
我就说我闻到了水果蛋糕味儿
I told you I smelled fruitcake.
你太客气了
You shouldn't have.
少来了 我很乐意
Bite your tongue. It's my pleasure.
看上去很好吃
It looks scrumptious.
话说 尼尔和我要去唱颂歌 一起来吗
Say, Neil and I are going caroling, you care to join?
我们也想…
You know we would…
但我的后背 烦人的又跟我闹腾了
It's my back. Darn thing's giving me fits.
太可惜了
That's a shame.
- 那圣诞快乐了 - 你也是 亲爱的
- Well, Merry Christmas. - And to you too, dear.
我们明天还打桥牌吧
Are we still on for bridge tomorrow?
绝对的
With bells on.
太好了
Yes.
- 好 再见 - 再见
- Okay, bye. - Bye-bye.
我们到哪了
Now, where were we?
现在怎么办 常青木桩在地下室
What do we do now? The evergreen stakes are in the basement.
我们需要另找常青木了 迪恩
Well, we need more evergreen, Dean.
我可能找到了
I think I just found us some more.
帮我堵门
Help me get this.
你个小家伙
You little thing.
我喜欢那棵树呢
I loved that tree.
玛姬
Madge!
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
萨姆 醒醒
Sam, wake up.
爸爸来过了 看他带来了什么
Dad was here. Look what he brought.
- 爸爸来过吗 - 嗯
- Dad was here? - Yeah.
看啊 我们收获好大
Look at this. We made a killing.
他怎么不叫醒我
Why didn't he try to wake me up?
他叫了你好久呢
He tried to, like, a thousand times.
是吗
He did?
嗯
Yeah.
我不是说他会跟我们过圣诞节吗
Did I tell you he would give us Christmas or what?
去啊 去拆礼物
Go on. Dive in.
是什么
What is it?
蓝宝石芭比娃娃
Sapphire Barbie?
爸爸可能把你当女孩了
Dad probably thinks you're a girl.
闭嘴啦
Shut up.
打开那个
Open that one.
爸爸没来过 是吧
Dad never showed, did he?
他来了 我发誓
Yeah, he did. I swear.
迪恩 这些东西你哪弄来的
Dean, where did you get all this stuff?
街区前面的一栋好房子里
Nice house up the block.
我发誓 我不知道那是给女孩的礼物
I swear, I didn't know they were chick presents.
爸爸如果能回来 他肯定会回来的
Look, I'm sure dad would have been here if he could.
如果他还活着
If he's alive.
别那么说
Don't say that.
他当然还活着
Of course he's alive.
他是爸爸
He's dad.
给
Here.
拿着
Take this.
不
No.
那是给爸爸的
No, that's for dad.
爸爸骗了我
Dad lied to me.
我想把它给你
I want you to have it.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
我确定
I'm sure.
谢谢 萨姆
Thank you, Sam. I…
我很喜欢
I love it.
你买啤酒了吗
You get the beer?
这是怎么回事
What's all this?
你觉得呢
What do you think it is?
圣诞节啊
It's Christmas.
你为什么改主意了
What made you change your mind?
来
Here,
尝尝蛋酒
try the eggnog.
如果酒劲不够告诉我
Let me know if it needs some more kick.
- 不用 挺好 - 是吗
- No, we're good. - Yeah?
- 嗯 - 那好 那…
- Yeah. - Good. Well,
坐吧 我们过圣诞节吧
have a seat. Let's do Christmas stuff or whatever.
好 重要的事先做
All right, first thing's first.
圣诞快乐 萨姆
Merry Christmas, Sam.
你哪买来的
Where did you get these?
特别的地方
Someplace special.
街那边的加油站
Gas mart down the street.
打开吧
Open them up.
嗯
Yeah.
英雄所见略同 迪恩
Great minds think alike, Dean.
真的吗
Really?
给
Here you go.
哇
Come on.
好啊
Yeah.
色情杂志
Skin mags…
还有
and.
剃须膏
shaving cream.
喜欢吗
You like?
嗯
Yeah, yeah.
看看这个
Well, look at this.
我的燃料 宝贝车的燃料
Fuel for me and fuel for my baby.
这太棒了 谢谢
These are awesome. Thanks.
那好
Good.
圣诞快乐 哥们
Merry Christmas, bro.
嗯
Yeah, yeah.
来 圣诞快乐
Here, Merry Christmas.
迪恩
Dean.
你想看比赛吗
Do you feel like watching the game?
当然
Absolutely.
那好
All right.